Guide to the Association of Fundraising Professionals Records, Western Pennsylvania Chapter, 1980-2005 AIS.2003.10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Association of Fundraising Professionals, Western Pennsylvania Chapter, Records
1980-2005
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Association of Fundraising Professionals. Western Pennsylvania Chapter
AIS.2003.10
7.51 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
The Association of Fundraising Professionals, Western Pennsylvania Chapter was established in 1980. They are one of 200 chapters worldwide. The chapter is made up of members from western Pennsylvania, eastern Ohio, West Virginia, and western Maryland. Their papers highlight the work they have done since 1980 to promote the goals of the Association of Fundraising Professionals, which is to "advance philanthropy through advocacy, research, education and certification programs."
History
The Association of Fundraising Professionals, formerly known as the National Society of Fund Raising Executives (NSFRE), was founded in 1960 to be a leader in the philanthropy world. Its goals are to promote stewardship, donor trust, and effective and ethical fundraising. Twenty years later, in 1980, eighteen members founded the Association of Fundraising Professionals, Western Pennsylvania Chapter (AFP-WPA).
The Western Pennsylvania Chapter was born out of necessity. There were a number of members who did not have a locally affiliated chapter. B. Jeanne Williams called for a gathering of NSFRE members and interested parties to establish a chapter in Western PA. After two meetings, they all agreed to start a chapter.
AFP-WPA's charter was accepted on September 5, 1980 and six days later on September 11 they held their first official meeting. At the time of its inception, Jeanne Williams was the acting chairman of the chapter. Thirty-six people were in attendance as J. Richard Wilson, Executive Vice President of NSFRE, gave his predictions for the future of the new chapter. By December of the same year, Warren Dana was elected the first President of AFP-WPA.
At the beginning of 1981, AFP-WPA had already begun putting together a newsletter to act as evidence of their progress. Their chapter by-laws had been approved, and they had sent a representative, Jeanne Williams, to the national meeting to represent their chapter.
By 1982 the chapter was running full-force, holding meetings each month, planning seminars for training and membership growth, holding luncheons, and continuing to release its newsletter to members so that everyone was kept up-to-date within the chapter.
Since these beginning years, AFP-WPA has continued to grow; its membership has risen to more than 400 fundraising professionals. They actively participate in the National Philanthropy Day, which was started by AFP in 1986. Also, they continue to attend the international conferences sponsored by AFP and held around the country. The chapter has been commended multiple times by the local government for its participation in fundraising initiatives. In 2005 Mayor Tom Murphy of Pittsburgh announced that November 15 would be "National Philanthropy Day" in Pittsburgh. This announcement was accompanied by many like it from government officials in Allegheny County and Washington County. Also a "Fund Raising Day" was proclaimed by Allegheny County in April 1998.
Scope and Content Notes
The records from AFP-WPA highlight the activity of the chapter from the point of its inception in 1980 to 2005. The meeting minutes of the chapter ranging from 1980 through 1999 show the focus of the chapter as it has evolved and grown over the years. There are also the collected newsletters of the local chapter and the national foundation chronicling the activities of both. Brochures and paperwork for National Philanthropy Day and Fund Raising Day provide a look into two of the major days of the chapter's programming year.
The majority of the records in this collection pertain to the 1990s.
Arrangement
The contents of the collection are organized into seven series:
Series I. Meeting Minutes
Series II. Presidents' Records (1985-2005)
Series III. National Philanthropy Day
Series IV. Fund Raising Day
Series V. NSFRE Conference and National Assembly Materials
Series VI. Chapter and National Publications
Series VII. Media
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Association of Fundraising Professionals, Western Pennsylvania Chapter in October 2003.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Within the collection are two floppy discs, two 7 ½ ips audio reels, and one U-matic videotape; each of these requires special hardware to play.
Previous Citation
Association of Fundraising Professionals Records, Western Pennsylvania Chapter, 1980-2005, AIS.2003.10, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Bibliography
The AFP/Wiley Fund Development Series, published by Wiley, is an ongoing book series devoted to fundraising, non-profit, and philanthropic issues. A few of these books can be found through PittCat+ on the University of Pittsburgh's Library website.
Philanthropists; Newsletters; Associations; Minutes (Administrative records); Pennsylvania, Western; Fund Raising Day; National Philanthropy Day; Charities -- Pennsylvania, Western; Fund raising -- Pennsylvania, Western; Nonprofit organizations -- Pennsylvania, Western; Association of Fundraising Professionals. Western Pennsylvania Chapter; Association of Fundraising Professionals; Bartlett, Janet; Duckaz, Bohdan; Emery, Janet C.; Markowitz, Rosalyn; National Society of Fund Raising Executives; Omiros, George J.; Petrucelli, Karen A.; Williams, Jeanne M.
- Meeting Minutes, 1980-1999; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  These files contain the minutes of board meetings, annual meetings, and some committee meetings. They act as evidence of the Chapter's activities and membership. The material in this series dates from 1980 to 1999; however the majority of the material dates from 1995 to 1999.
  - Chapter Meeting, September 11, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chapter Meeting, October 9, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chapter Meeting, December 18, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chapter Meeting, January 8, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chapter Meeting, July 15, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1989 Fund Raising Day Committee, October 13, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Retreat, August 6, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, September 19, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NSFRE Board of Directors, November 8, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - NSFRE President's Meeting, June 5, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, October 20, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Executive Meeting, December 1, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting, January 13, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board Meeting, February 16, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board Meeting, March 16, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board Meeting, May 18, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board Meeting, June 15, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Annual Meeting, June 15, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board Planning Meeting, August 23, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Program Committee Meeting, August 24, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - PA State Issues Task Force Meeting, September 18, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting, September 21, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting, October 19, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Board Meeting, November 9, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Board Meeting, January 16, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Board Meeting, February 15, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Board Meeting, April 18, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Board Meeting, May 16, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Board Meeting, June 20, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Annual Meeting, June 20, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Board Planning Retreat, July 12, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Diversity Committee Meeting, September 10, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, September 19, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, October 24, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, November 19, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Memberships Election of Nominating Committee Members, January 16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Board of Directors Retreat, January 29, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - General Membership Meeting, February 20, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March 20, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, April 24, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, May 15, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, June 19, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Annual Meeting, June 19, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Board of Directors Planning Retreat, August 8, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Board Meeting, September 18, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Board Meeting, October 16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Board Meeting, November 18, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Board of Directors Mid-Year Retreat, January 12, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, February 19, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March 19, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, May 21, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, June 18, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Annual Meeting, June 18, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Board of Directors Planning Retreat, August 4, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, September 17, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, October 15, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, December 10, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Annual Meeting, December 10, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, January 21, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, February 18, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March 18, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Board of Directors Planning Retreat, March 24, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, May 20, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, June 17, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Presidents Minutes, July 19, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, August 19, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, September 16, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, October 21, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Board of Directors Planning Retreat, November 22, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Annual Meeting, December 8, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, December 8, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Presidential Records, 1985-2005; II.
  These are the files of the President of AFP-WPA through the years 1985 to 2005. The files contain information on the chapter (by-laws, public relations, financial statements, etc.), projects, and individual members. The material in this series dates from 1985 to 2005; however the majority of the material dates from 1991 to 1999.
  - Financial Statements, 1991, 1993, 1999-2006 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Healthcare Development Forum, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - NSFRE Ideas, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - NSFRE "First Course", November 1985 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - NSFRE Ohio/Midwest Conference, November 11-12, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Planned Giving Council Programs, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Planned Giving Minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Planned Giving Newsletters, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NSFRE Public Service Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - NSFRE Renewal, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chapter President Memos, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NSFRE Annual Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NSFRE Check Requests, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - NSFRE Ethics Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - NSFRE First Course, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - NSFRE Five Star Awards, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - NSFRE Survey/Certification Course, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chapter Leadership Workshops, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - NSFRE Legislative Affairs Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - NSFRE Incorporation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - NSFRE Membership Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - NSFRE Selections Committee, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - NSFRE Scholarship News Release, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Scholarship to International Conference, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - NPWA Chapter Sponsorship, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - NSFRE-WPA CFRE Survey, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Strategic Planning, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - NSFRE Letterhead, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - NSFRE Foundation Data, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - NSFRE Developments, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - NSFRE Developments, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Fund Raising for Novices, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - NSFRE Diversity, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - NSFRE Administrative Services, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - NSFRE Leadership Letters, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - NSFRE E.L.I. (Executive Leadership Institute), 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - NSFRE Youth Program, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - NSFRE Institute Annual Report, 1985 and 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Chapter Information, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - NSFRE Legislative Affairs Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NSFRE Nominating Committee, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - NSFRE (ACFRE), 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NSFRE Public Relations Committee Survey, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - NSFRE Developments/Loose Papers, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Grassroots Project, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - External Affairs, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Fund Raising Day, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Membership, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Memorial Contributions, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Metro Listing, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - First Course, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - National Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Job Description, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Continuing Education, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Collaborative Relationships, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Holiday Party, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Expenses, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Five Star Award, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Ethics, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Focus Group, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Fund Raising for Novices, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Committee Volunteers, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - International Conference Scholarship, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Internal Affairs, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Internship, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Volunteer in the 21st Century, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Leadership Workshops, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Mailing Lists, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Paid Administrator, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - International Conference, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - President's Acceptance Speech, JAB, June 18, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - NSFRE By-Laws, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - NSFRE Budgets, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Certification, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Chapter Treasury Campaign, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Diversity Committee, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ethics Committee, 1995 and 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Training, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Legal/Financial, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Income/Expense Transmittal Forms NSFRE, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - NSFRE Fiscal Year Adjustment, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Five Star Award, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Foundation Committee, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Benchmark Presentation, Fund Raising Day, April 7, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - NSFRE Goals, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Grassroots Pilot Program, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - NSFRE Leave a Legacy, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Legislative Information, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Chapter Leadership, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - NSFRE Luncheon, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Membership Application, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mentoring Program, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - NSFRE National Assembly, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - New Governance Structure, May 1998 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Organizational Chart, Board of Directors, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Position Descriptions, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - NSFRE Position Descriptions, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Outreach Committee, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh Planned Giving Council, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - President's Message – National, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Board Planning Meeting, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Annual Chapter Plan, 1993-1994, 1996-1997, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Public Relations, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - President's Mailings, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Program Committee, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - NSFRE – Resignations, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Board Retreat, January 12, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Board Retreat, August 8, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Strategic Direction 2000, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - NSFRE Scholarship Program, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - NSFRE Nominating Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - National Philanthropy Day – Barbara N. Trehar, CFRE (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Awards Committee – Dee Jay Oshry, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Awards Committee – Dolly Ellenberg, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Special Chapter Consultants – Fred Leasure and Greg Omiros, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Janet A. Bartlett – Expenses to Rebecca, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Foundation – Diane M. Banna and Elliot S. Oshry, CFRE, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Every Member Campaign, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - IPP – Janet C. Emery, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Nominating Committee – Janet C. Emery, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Historian – Jill Murchak, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - VP Education – Wayne R. Fedele, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Fund Raising Day – Laurie Anderson, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Program Committee – Scott M. Jones and Martha Tiani, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Ethics Education – Roberta Moore, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Ethics Education – Linda Maynard, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Certification – Jane Berkey, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - VP Membership – Sharron Sherrill, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Assistant VP Membership – Jerry Mote, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Outreach Committee – Patricia S. Holmes, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Diversity Committee – Jeffrey Richardson, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - VP Communication Services – Larry Karnoff, CFRE, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Legislative Information – Karen Galentine, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Public Relations – Barbara L. Becker, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Scholarship – William D. Speidel, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Certification – Karen Petrucelli, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Member Recognition and Newsletter – Tammy Aupperly, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Treasurer – Rebecca A. Hebert, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Secretary – Celia A. Hindes, CFRE, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - General Correspondence, Janet A. Bartlett, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence to National – Janet A. Bartlett, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence Janet faxed to NSFRE members, June, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence Janet faxed to NSFRE members, June, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Administrator, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Annual Reports, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Archive Project and Transfer or Records Report, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence to NSFRE Board Members, July 1991 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Chapter Membership List, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Updated By-Laws, September 20, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - NSFRE – WPA Budget, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - NSFRE – WPA Schedule of Programs, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - NSFRE – WPA Officers, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Newsletter Budgets, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - NSFRE Annual Report, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Chapter Award for "Every Member Campaign", 1997 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Development Summit Brochures, 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - NSFRE – WPA Board Job Descriptions, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Holiday Party Information, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Draft for Annual Plan, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Program Evaluation – Legislative Affairs, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Program Evaluation – Prospect Research for Grass Roots Organization, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Program Evaluation – Grantmakers' Common Application Form, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Scholarship Information, June 20, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - NSFRE – WPA Board Member List, July 15, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - NSFRE – WPA Board Member List, January 10, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Board of Directors Retreat, July 12, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Fee Vote, March 7, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Nominating Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Nominees for Director at Large, December 1, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - National Philanthropy Day Resolution Co-Sponsors as of, July 10, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - NSFRE Public Relations Committee Plan, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Association of Fundraising Professionals – Chapter Presidents List, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 98)
- National Philanthropy Day, 1987-2005; III.
  These are the files pertaining to National Philanthropy Day. The files are arranged chronologically starting with National Philanthropy Day 1987. It is celebrated each year in November. Also present in the files are government proclamations from counties around the Pittsburgh area formally recognizing National Philanthropy Day.
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 11, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 10, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 16, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 19, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 17, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 16, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 14, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 19, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 18, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 19, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 16, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - National Philanthropy Day, December 6, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 14, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 19, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 18, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Butler County, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Westmoreland County, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, October 27, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Fayette County, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - City of Pittsburgh, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, October 19, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - City of Pittsburgh, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Allegheny County, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, November 15, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Washington County, PA recognizes National Philanthropy Day, November 1, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Fund Raising Day, 1987-2005; IV.
  These are the files pertaining to Fund Raising Day. Fund Raising Day is another day like National Philanthropy Day. It is held each year and includes meetings and conferences. These files are arranged chronologically starting with Fundraising Day 1990. Also present is one county government recognition of Fund Raising Day.